[Music]
We've probably got an anniversary
of 50 years next year of growing.
We're second generation.
We currently have a third generation
on board, which is pretty encouraging.
- Yeah, we've got a fair bit of work
ahead of us, I think.
- We're thinning.
- And no backpackers.
- No, that's going to be the challenge:
our staffing levels at the moment.
I think generally farming is probably
something that's in your blood.
I always had a passion from a young age
to grow stuff.
I've done nothing else but grow fruit.
I've lived where I currently live
for about 49 or 50 years
of my 52 years of life.
You get into a situation where it's not
a forced situation. It's a good lifestyle.
The only problem is the amount of hours
you work a week.
We do 60 hours as a quiet week,
and 80's not uncommon.
Since Gavin and I have been in business
together, which is 26, 27 years,
we've probably achieved what
two generations do
in our time frame together.
We've built a pretty big pack house.
We've got a fair-sized business happening.
It's been a lot of work,
and we haven't necessarily always had,
as we always put it, old money
to help you along the way.
It's been sink or swim,
and we've been swimming pretty hard.
Well, we used to grow a lot of cherries
years ago,
and just through
the cherry association meetings,
Tom was always there and in our ear:
"Give me a go, give me a go."
It would be 14, 15, 16 years,
something like that,
since we first gave him a try on one block
that was struggling a little bit.
Now we use Hybrid Ag fertilisers
across the whole farm.
[Music]